Tesfalem Tekie

Software Developer

(512) 888 6300



tes.tekie85@gmail.com



in LinkedIn/Tesfalem



GitHub/Tesfalem

Motivated and passionate Software Developer with over 6+ years of hands-on experience. Dedicated to web application development and design, with a keen focus on delivering quality results within deadlines. Adaptable to changing and challenging environments.

Technical Skills

Front-end: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap, SASS, jQuery, React.js

Back-end: Java SE, Java EE (Servlets, JSP), JSON, Spring boot, Spring Data JPA, Maven, Thymeleaf, Object-Oriented Programming, REST APIs, Apache Tomcat, Test-Driven Development

Database: MySQL, PostgreSQL, AWS environment, SQL, Paired Programming

Tools: Docker, Kubernetes, CI/CD pipeline, Version Control with Git/Github, Postman, Jira, Operating System (Microsoft, Mac, and Linux), Bash, PowerShell

Professional Experience

Appddiction Studio, LLC - San Antonio, TX **Software Developer** | Feb 2023 - Present

- Created more than 4 full-stack web applications which processed, analyzed, and visualized data for different clients.
- Ensured that applications were secure and that they can interact with multiple APIs and databases.
- Collaborated with the app development team, including the project manager, developers, and quality assurance specialist to identify problems, testing methods, and best practices.
- Managed time-sensitive updates, such as changing content and upgrading databases.
- Worked within tight deadlines in a fast-paced development environment.

Lwam Tech - Arlington, VA

Software Engineer | Mar 2021 - Aug 2022

- Designed, Developed, and supported backend applications and services for web platforms and Spring-based enterprise applications to provide configuration information to web applications.
- Actively participated and contributed to product development and SDLC including design, development, testing, and maintenance of integrated software applications.
- Developed Web application with REST API backend using JDBC for database connectivity.
- Designed and developed various abstract classes and interfaces to construct the business logic using Java.
- Fair understanding of Microservices.

Baxter Healthcare, Chicago, IL Frontend Developer | June 2018 - Feb 2021

- Implemented and maintained front-end web applications, resulting in a 10% increase in website traffic and conversion rates.
- Participated in Agile/Sprint methodologies to do requirements gathering, analysis, and planning.
- Developed and deployed an application that effectively reduces the website's page loading time by 20% by implementing JavaScript compression and CSS minification techniques.
- Worked with an agile team of 12 members and provided end-to-end solutions to clients
- Optimized application for maximum speed and scalability.

Atlantic Union Bank, Richmond, VA

Frontend Developer | May 2016 - Apr 2018

- Implemented and maintained front-end web applications, resulting in a 20% reduction in page load speeds and conversion rates by utilizing modern web technologies such as React.js and best practices for user experience and accessibility.
- Assisted in the development and maintenance of front-end web applications, resulting in a positive impact on the company's overall performance.
- Developed and executed front-end development strategies, resulting in a 15% increase in website performance by implementing optimization techniques such as code minification and troubleshooting issues using browser developer tools.
- Worked with cross-functional teams to develop and execute on-time and on-budget projects and initiatives by effectively communicating project timelines, progress, and objectives using tools such as Slack and Zoom.

Education

Codeup Bootcamp Certification of Completion

Aug 2022 - Jan 2023

A fully-immersive, project-based, and intensive Full-Stack Java Career Accelerator that provides students with expert instruction in software development

San Antonio College Associate of Computer Science

Jan 2018 - Dec 2019

Completed two years of undergrad computer Science

Eritrea Institute of Technology (EIT) Bachelor of Science, Electrical Engineering

Sep 2006 - May 2011
Completed four years of undergrad degree

Certification

Certified SAFe Scrum 6.0 Certified SAFe for Architects